This incident is the greatest scandal in the history of the Czech Police!
Quest'incidente è il più grande scandalo nella storia della polizia ceca!
Regrettably, the three murdered men
Purtroppo, le tre vittime
had connections with the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
avevano legami con l'ex polizia segreta cecoslovacca.
I'd like to believe that
Mi piacerebbe credere
these murders have wiped out all unsavory ties to the Prague station.
che, dopo questi omicidi, tali legami con la centrale di Praga non esistano più.
You are all officers of this proud Czech Police force.
Siete agenti della gloriosa forza di polizia ceca.
I expect you all to act honorably.
Mi aspetto che vi comportiate tutti con onore.
As the new commissioner, I will work to regain people's trust.
Come nuovo commissario, m'impegnerò per riconquistare la fiducia della gente.
I will implement thorough reforms.
E attuerò delle radicali riforme.
Let me introduce the five members
Ora, vi presento i cinque membri della task force speciale
I expect you to cooperate with them
Mi aspetto che collaboriate con loro
so these atrocious crimes can be solved as quickly as possible.
per venire velocemente a capo di questi atroci crimini.
Detective Suk, I presume.
Il detective Suk, presumo.
Yes, sir.
Sissignore.
As the new commissioner, I'd like to express my appreciation
Come nuovo commissario, le esprimo il mio apprezzamento
for your work on this case.
per il suo lavoro su questo caso.
Thank you.
Grazie.
Incidentally, what case are you working on now?
A proposito, a quale caso sta lavorando, ora?
The case Inspector Zeman was working on, the murder of Petrov,
A quello di cui si stava occupando l'ispettore Zeman, l'omicidio Petrov.
the man running the unlicensed orphanage.
La vittima gestiva un orfanotrofio illegale.
I see.
Capisco.
Continue working on your investigation.
Continui con la sua indagine, allora.
Yes, sir. I'll be going then.
Sissignore. Vado subito.
Wait. There's one other thing.
Aspetti. C'è un'altra cosa.
About that tall man who's a suspect in the murder of Inspector Zeman,
Riguardo a quell'uomo alto sospettato dell'omicidio dell'ispettore Zeman,
have you found out anything about him?
ha scoperto qualcosa nel corso delle sue indagini?
No. I haven't found anything.
No. Non ho trovato niente.
I see. You may go now.
Capisco. Può andare.
Thank you, sir.
Grazie, signore.
"Jan Suk."
"Jan Suk.
"Assigned to Prague Station a year ago."
Assegnato alla centrale di Praga un anno fa.
"Had a close relationship with Inspector Zeman since he started."
Ha avuto da subito un legame stretto con l'ispettore Zeman.
"Exposed the hidden past of both detectives Patera and Janáček."
Ha denunciato il passato nascosto dei detective Patera e Janáček.
"Met with Commissioner Hamrlík just before his death."
Ha incontrato il commissario Hamrlík poco prima che morisse."
-Keep an eye on that man. -Yes, sir.
- Dobbiamo tenerlo d'occhio. - Sissignore.
Hi.
Salve.
I was pretty happy when you answered the phone
Sono stato felice che mi abbia risposto
at the hotel that you said you were staying at.
all'hotel in cui aveva detto di stare.
Did you think you have been betrayed again?
Pensava di essere stato tradito di nuovo?
Well…
Beh…
An orange juice.
Un succo d'arancia.
Mr. Grimmer, you said we should meet in a crowded place.
Sig. Grimmer, ha detto d'incontrarci in un posto affollato.
Are you sure it's all right?
Sicuro che vada bene?
Is what all right?
Di cosa parla?
The new commissioner still suspects you in the murder of Inspector Zeman.
Il nuovo commissario sospetta ancora di lei per l'omicidio di Zeman.
The former Czechoslovakia secret police are still after you too, right?
L'ex polizia segreta cecoslovacca le dà la caccia.
-There are no safe places. -What?
- Non ci sono posti sicuri. - Cosa?
If someone wants to get me, they can do it anywhere.
Se qualcuno vuole arrivare a me, può farlo ovunque.
For example, they could do it from that window with red curtains.
Per esempio, potrebbero colpirmi da quella finestra con le tende rosse.
Mr. Grimmer, who exactly are you?
Sig. Grimmer, lei chi è esattamente?
Just a struggling journalist.
Solo un giornalista che fa del suo meglio.
What? Then why are these things happening to you?
Cosa? Allora perché le sta succedendo tutto questo?
It's probably because I stuck my nose in too deep.
Forse perché ho ficcato troppo il naso.
It's nothing to laugh about!
Non è una cosa su cui scherzare!
They tried to take your life.
Poteva rimetterci la vita!
-I don't mind. -Huh?
- Non m'importa. - Eh?
I knew this might happen when I snooped around.
Ero consapevole dei rischi.
Presently, Suk is at a cafe in Republic Square.
Al momento, Suk è in un bar a Republic Square.
Like we suspected, he's meeting that tall man.
Come sospettavamo, si vede con quell'uomo alto.
It's Grimmer for sure.
È di sicuro Grimmer.
Yes, sir. Should I just keep him under surveillance?
Sì, signore. Mi limito a tenerlo d'occhio?
So it happened when you were investigating Petrov
Quindi è successo tutto mentre indagava su Petrov
who had conducted brainwashing experiments
che aveva condotto esperimenti di lavaggio del cervello sui bambini
That's right.
Esatto.
Then just before Petrov died,
E, poco prima di morire,
he gave you that key to a safe deposit box?
Petrov le ha dato quella chiave che apre una cassetta di sicurezza?
Yes. He also mentioned the "origin of the monster."
Sì. Ha anche parlato di "origine del mostro".
"Origin of the monster"?
"Origine del mostro"?
I don't know what it means,
Non so cosa significhi,
but a lot of people seem to want to get their hands on it.
ma molte persone sembrano volerci mettere le mani sopra.
The former secret police?
L'ex polizia segreta?
And a blonde-haired woman.
E una donna bionda.
The children from the orphanage also told me that after Petrov was killed,
I bambini dell'orfanotrofio mi hanno detto che, dopo la morte di Petrov,
they saw a beautiful blonde-haired woman leave the building.
hanno visto una bellissima donna bionda lasciare l'edificio.
Do you know who that might be?
Sa chi potrebbe essere?
I haven't got the faintest idea.
Non ne ho la più pallida idea.
-Are you all right? -Huh?
- Mi dica, sta bene? - Eh?
You're hiding the fact that you're meeting with me from your superiors, aren't you?
Ha tenuto nascosto il suo incontro con me ai suoi superiori.
You're okay with betraying the police?
Le sta bene tradire la polizia?
It's not like I'm hiding it.
Non sto nascondendo nulla.
I'm exercising investigatory discretion.
Sto solo esercitando discrezione.
After investigating thoroughly, I'll report everything.
Quando avrò concluso le indagini, riferirò tutto.
I'll be able to prove your innocence after a proper investigation.
E potrò dimostrare la sua innocenza.
What's wrong?
Cosa c'è che non va?
Slowly look to your left.
Guardi alla sua sinistra.
What?
Cosa?
The man reading a paper under a parasol to your left looks suspicious.
L'uomo che legge il giornale sotto l'ombrellone
-He's from the secret police? -He could be.
- È della polizia segreta? - Forse.
Anyway, ready to go?
Comunque, è pronto ad andare?
Go where?
Andare? Dove?
You brought it, right?
L'ha portata, no?
The key to the safe deposit box that I gave you.
La chiave della cassetta di sicurezza che le ho dato.
Yes.
Sì.
Don't you want to know the truth about this "monster"?
Non vuole sapere la verità su questo "mostro"?
I do.
Sì.
Then let's get going.
Andiamo, allora.
But you may be better off not knowing.
Ma per lei sarebbe meglio non saperne nulla.
You're looking pretty pale.
È impallidito.
That woman's close.
Quella donna è vicina.
Is something wrong?
È successo qualcosa?
No. I must be imagining things.
No. Probabilmente ho iniziato a immaginarmi le cose.
Suk's on the move.
Suk si sta muovendo.
I'll follow.
Li seguo.
I'm Suk from the Prague Police. I called earlier.
Sono Suk della polizia di Praga. Ho chiamato prima.
One moment, please.
Un momento, per favore.
Thank you for waiting.
Grazie per l'attesa.
Please, I'll show you the way.
Prego, vi faccio strada.
The safe deposit boxes are in here.
Le cassette di sicurezza sono qui.
You may use that room to examine the contents.
Potete usare quella stanza per esaminarne il contenuto.
Research papers and a cassette tape.
Documenti di ricerca e una cassetta.
I brought a tape recorder.
Beh, io ho portato un mangianastri.
Are you ready? I'll play it.
È pronto? La faccio partire.
Where are you?
Dove ti trovi?
Kinderheim 511.
Al Kinderheim 511.
That's the voice of a child.
È la voce di un bambino.
What is your name?
Come ti chiami?
My name is…
Io mi chiamo
Johan.
Johan.
What's your last name?
E qual è il tuo cognome?
I'll ask you again.
Te lo chiedo di nuovo.
What is your last name?
Qual è il tuo cognome?
My name is…
Io mi chiamo
Otto.
Otto.
Hans.
Hans.
My name is… Thomas.
Io mi chiamo Thomas.
My name is…
Io mi chiamo…
Which is your real name?
Qual è il tuo vero nome?
there lived a nameless monster.
un mostro senza nome.
The monster was dying to have a name.
Il mostro desiderava ardentemente avere un nome.
Is that some kind of story?
È una specie di favola?
I was waiting for Anna.
Stavo aspettando Anna.
Who is Anna?
Chi è Anna?
I was waiting for Anna…
Stavo aspettando Anna
while reading a picture book.
mentre leggevo un libro illustrato.
The boy was drugged before he was questioned.
Il ragazzo era stato drogato prima di essere interrogato.
Where is your father?
Dov'è tuo padre?
I don't know.
Non lo so.
Where is your mother?
E tua madre?
I think she's alive.
Credo sia viva.
You're a very gifted child.
Sei un bambino molto dotato.
Is there anything you're afraid of?
C'è qualcosa che ti spaventa?
What are you most afraid of?
Qual è la tua paura più grande?
Let me ask a different question.
Ti farò una domanda diversa.
Have you ever killed anyone?
Hai mai ucciso qualcuno?
Lots of people died.
Sono morte molte persone.
It was like… it was just Anna and me in the world.
Era come… se ci fossimo solo io e Anna al mondo.
Where was that?
Dov'è successo questo?
Let's go back to the other question.
Torniamo alla domanda di prima.
What are you most afraid of?
Qual è la tua paura più grande?
The monster inside me is getting bigger and bigger.
Il mostro dentro di me sta diventando enorme.
Munch-munch, chomp-chomp, gobble-gobble, gulp.
Chomp-chomp, crunch-crunch, gnam-gnam, gulp.
The thing I am afraid of the most…
La cosa che più mi spaventa
is…
è…
I'm feeling sick! I'm going to throw up!
Mi sento male! Sto per vomitare!
Are you all right, Mr. Grimmer?
Tutto bene, sig. Grimmer?
Yes…
Sì.
What the heck is this tape?
Che significa questo nastro?
Is that who the monster is?
È questo il mostro di cui parlano?
I don't understand it at all.
Non ci capisco nulla.
We may not understand it,
Magari a noi questa storia non è chiara,
but there are still people who want it more than anything else.
ma c'è chi vuole questa cassetta più di ogni altra cosa.
Like the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
Come l'ex polizia segreta cecoslovacca.
It doesn't matter whether we listen to some of it or all of it,
Non importa se la ascoltiamo tutta o in parte.
there's no going back for us now.
Ormai, non possiamo più tornare indietro.
What will you do with that tape and those reports?
Cosa farà con il nastro e i documenti?
Put them back in the safe deposit box?
Li rimetterà nella cassetta di sicurezza?
No. Ordinarily, I'd leave them here as evidence.
No. Normalmente, li avrei lasciati qui come prova.
But you'll take them?
Invece li porterà via?
Then we should leave separately.
Allora, dovremmo andarcene separatamente.
I'm pretty sure it's me that they're after.
Sono io quello a cui danno la caccia. Seguiranno me.
Oh, right. Tell me your phone number and home address.
Oh, giusto. Mi dia il suo numero e il suo indirizzo.
If we make it back safely, let's contact each other.
Se rientriamo sani e salvi, sentiamoci.
I made it home okay.
Sono tornato a casa sano e salvo.
I'm getting a bad feeling.
Ho una brutta sensazione.
His place is on Lanover Street, huh?
Abita a Lanover Street, eh?
What's this all about?
Che diavolo succede?
That's what we would like to know.
È quello che vorremmo sapere noi.
You know who we are, right?
Sai chi siamo, vero?
You're members of the special task force from headquarters.
Siete la task force speciale inviata dal quartier generale.
What are you two doing at my place?
Che ci fate a casa mia?
How long have you been meeting Grimmer?
Da quanto ti vedi con Grimmer?
And don't tell us you haven't.
E non negarlo.
You met him earlier at a cafe in Republic Square
L'hai incontrato prima in un bar a Republic Square
and then went to Prochazka Bank.
e poi siete andati alla Procházka Bank.
You know the man in this picture, don't you?
Conosci l'uomo in questa foto, vero?
He's Captain Karel Ranke.
È il capitano Karel Ranke.
He was a big shot in the Czechoslovakia secret police who went underground.
Era un pezzo grosso della polizia segreta cecoslovacca.
I don't know that man.
Io… Non conosco quell'uomo.
We checked your bank account.
Ho controllato il tuo conto in banca.
There was a large deposit this month. What's it from?
C'è stato un grosso deposito questo mese. Da dove viene?
What?
Cosa?
What are you talking about? I don't know about any deposit!
Di cosa sta parlando? Non ne so niente!
Your mother is hospitalized
Tua madre è ricoverata
at the Krumlov National Hospital with a serious illness, isn't she?
all'ospedale nazionale Krumlov per una grave malattia, vero?
It must cost a bundle just to cover hospital expenses.
Dev'essere molto costoso farla curare lì.
What are you implying?
Cosa state insinuando?
After your mother divorced your father, she raised you alone.
Dopo il divorzio da tuo padre, tua madre ti ha cresciuto da sola.
You're very close to your mother, aren't you?
Gli sei molto affezionato, no?
We're going to search your place.
Perquisiremo casa tua.
Fine, look all you like.
Bene, fate pure.
I'm not hiding anything!
Non ho niente da nascondere!
Look all you like.
Frugate quanto vi pare.
Zander, come here a sec.
Zander, vieni qui un attimo.
What are these?
Cos'è questa roba?
They were in a cabinet in your bathroom.
Era in un armadietto nel tuo bagno.
I've never seen these before.
Non l'ho mai vista prima.
We can't tell what the drug is until It's been tested at the station.
Non sapremo cos'è questo farmaco finché non verrà analizzato.
But the muscle relaxant that killed
Ma il miorilassante che ha ucciso
the three men at the station was found in…
i tre uomini alla stazione di polizia era contenuto…
whiskey bonbons they ate.
in dei cioccolatini al whisky.
Come with us to the station.
Devi venire con noi in centrale.
Fine, I will.
Nessun problema.
Question me all you like.
Interrogatemi quanto volete.
We will.
Lo faremo.
I'm sorry,
Solo una cosa.
but could I change my shirt before I go?
Posso cambiarmi la camicia prima di andare?
Sure, that's fine.
Certo, va bene.
Stay calm.
Devo stare calmo.
I haven't done anything wrong.
Non ho fatto niente di male.
If I explain everything, they'll understand.
Se gli spiego tutto, capiranno.
I smell gunpowder smoke.
È odore di polvere da sparo.
Suk!
Suk!